

Akshay Chaturvedi

Contact: +91 8192948040 Email: ac.nawab@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/PM-Akshay-chaturvedi



Product Owner with 7 years of experience in spearheading conversion, optimization, and development of Enterprise, B2B, and B2C Products in Hospitality, Access Control, and E-commerce Sectors. Led teams of 5-14 people across technology, business and design.

KEY SKILLS:

• Product Roadmap • Product Vision • Stakeholder Management • Requirement Gathering • Agile • Scrum Methodologies • Prioritization • Product Strategy • UAT • API Integration • Market Research • UX • Sprint Planning • Sprint Review and Retrospective • Product Ideation • SDLC • Access Management • CI/CD

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Net Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Duration: July 2023 – Present Designation: Sr. Business Analyst

Role: Product Owner

- Communicated product vision, led cross-functional teams to innovate features and streamlined timelines for product delivery.
- Prioritized the product backlog, analyzed team's progression on sprint, reviewed wireframes and UI, reducing design rework by 30%.
- Presented milestone-focused reports to internal and external stakeholders, conducted user acceptance tests and impactful product demos while managing end-to-end product life cycle.
- Facilitated backlog refinement, sprint planning, retrospective sessions, planned releases and maintained a strategic roadmap aligned with business goals resulting 95% product deliveries on time.
- Defined MVP deliverables for B2B ecommerce platform while building product from 0 to 1.
- Implemented advance forecasting algorithms and automated the Purchase Order flow, resulting in a 30% reduction in manual errors and a 20% increase in procurement efficiency.
- Augmented features for ERP, enhancing its functionality and usability for end users, resulting in a 25% increase in user adoption and satisfaction.
- Successfully delivered a B2B ERP & Supplier Portal platform with the ability for Buyers to optimize the inventory management for calculating cost of goods sold (COGS).

Nagarro Software Pvt. Ltd

Duration: August 2018 - June 2023

Designation: Staff Engineer (Lead – Technology)

Role: Product Owner

- Successfully rolled features on Hotel Management System (B2B SaaS), launched MVP products to simplify operations at various properties enhancing the user experience.
- Added Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) for the property management mobile and web applications, enhancing security and user management for 100+ property management users.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, led the development and deployment of mobile applications for Mobile Service Tool and Property Management Systems.
- Executed functional changes in the data warehousing modules to facilitate Room set up on the PMS application and established process facilitating order refinement, processing along with invoicing for B2B product's licenses.
- Automated the licensing portal resulting in a 41% reduction in response time and 30% increase in customer satisfaction score.

Honeywell International Pvt. Ltd

Duration: March 2016 – July 2018
Designation: Sr. Technical Support Specialist

- Maintained knowledge base repositories for new products, created product modules with specifications and wiring, rolled out the process updates for the new products being released.
- Coordinated with clients BU/BP, reported issues to R&D and supported BU/BP, Tech on site with docs, installation and commissioning while maintaining NPS above 80%.
- Assisted tech on-site with HVAC product functionality enhancing operational efficiency by 15%.

AutoMeter Alliance Pvt. Ltd

Duration: August 2015 – March 2016
Designation: Assistant Executive Engineer

- Managed the team of 15 technicians.
- Prepared daily workloads for staff & coordinated regarding the daily work allocation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology – Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering

University - Nagpur University

Year of Passing - 2011

IT SKILLS & Certifications

Tools: Azure DevOps, Taiga, Feature Map, Figma, Power BI, JIRA, Confluence, Miro, Notion

Technology: RFID, .net, React Native, Python, PL/SQL

Certifications:

• Executive Program in Product Management - XLRI	November 2023	Cert No: 20230638135
 Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) 	July 2022	Cert No: 001385577
Agile Scrum Foundation	April 2023	Cert No: 4294623
• PMI-ACP	May 2023	Cert No: 4347037
• PMI- RMP	May 2023	Cert No: 4345015
• CAPM	May 2023	Cert No: 4345087